Welcome back guys to another tutorial. This is part five,
and we're gonna be talking about product research, customer research.
Now we're really gonna be getting into the actual would say preparation phase,
the research phase, the marketing stuff, uh, before getting into an edit.
Alright, so this is how I do it. This is how we do it in our agency,
and everyone has a different process,
but you can learn and extract what you need from our process. So number one,
when it comes to product research, okay,
I've broken it into four different stages of product research.
Number one is identifying the product type.
Number two is identifying the primary benefits.
Number three is identifying the primary features.
And number four are identifying different use cases for the,
for the product itself. Now, if you don't, uh, work with products,
this could apply to courses, coaching, whatever the case may be. Um,
it's the same concept all, all throughout. Uh, but for this specific example,
we are gonna be talking about e-commerce physical product,
because that's what we're, that's what we're known for. Number one,
when it comes to product type,
you gotta understand the product type to determine the primary objective of the
creative.
And so we've actually developed our own categories for different product types,
because every product fits within a particular category,
which that category has, uh, a particular objective, uh,
when it comes to advertising, okay?
So we have 10 different e-commerce product types.
And so the main one that you're probably gonna see most often is the problem
solving product type. This purpose is to, the, the products are, are,
are meant to solve a problem, right? So you got kitchen, kitchen, gadgets,
electronics tools, fitness cars, whatever that is your, you know,
typical as seen on TV or problem solution. Very, very common one.
Number two is your lifestyle. This is products that enhance your,
your appearance, your aesthetics, right? This is clothing, jewelry, shoes, art,
car accessories, all the little, all all the artistics stuff.
That's, that's lifestyle. Number three is physical and, uh, transformation.
These are products that can transform your external appearances, okay?
Your physical, your physically transforming yourself, beauty and makeup,
hair and beard products, body composition, eye products, acne products,
skincare. Look, you're,
you're using this product and you're transforming your physical appearance.
Uh, number four is life extension.
These are products that will in increase your,
your livability so to speak, will allow you to live longer or be healthier.
Supplements, exercise products, health products. You're extending your life.
You're, if you use this product, you're going to live longer.
You're gonna be healthier, right? That's what we call it. Life extension. Uh,
I think this number five, life enhancing tech.
These are products that can improve your life through technology, electronics,
gadgets. That one's pretty straightforward. Next,
you have time saving and convenience products.
These things pretty straightforward there. Kitchen gadgets, cleaning products,
subscription boxes, chargers, what you know, that,
that one you see all the time, I'm sure. Next is gift and novelty.
These are products that are primarily used as gifts. Okay? So toys, games,
uh, writing materials you can even think of like cards of roses, tho,
that type of stuff. Um, next you have educational.
These are here to increase. Increase your intelligence,
increase your awareness, right? Toys, puzzles, art sets, children's foundations,
lots of, lots of, uh, kids toys and stuff like that. Uh, next,
next you have decoration products that are decorative and aesthetic.
You have canvas, art clocks, bedsheets, tapestries, lighting. Lastly,
you have print on demand.
These are products that are customizable with graphics and designs, clothing,
electronics, art. There's so many different types of those. Okay?
So the point of doing that before I move forward,
once you understand that every product fits within a a certain category,
then you know, okay, this is a, a physical transformational product. I know the,
the key objective here is we, we wanna show this thing working, right? We,
we need to show it transforming somebody's face or transforming someone's
appearance. That's gonna be the main selling point.
If it's a gift novelty product,
we wanna really highlight why this thing is the best gift for that individual.
If it's decorative,
we wanna show how this product is gonna look so much better in their house or
wherever or, or when they're wearing it, um,
and how much better it's gonna appeal to them, right?
So you kind of have to ask yourself those questions before getting started with
any type of project. Um, is understanding where do we fit in this?
And that becomes the primary benefit. Okay? So that's number two.
Primary benefits.
Benefits show how the product improves the customer's life. Okay?
I ask this question every time I hire someone new.
Can you tell me the difference between a benefit and a feature?
And most of the time people don't know what this, how to answer it,
but benefits improve the customer's life and features tell
you what the product is. Okay? So benefits sell, features tell,
that's a very easy way to remember it.
The key to identifying primary benefits is finding out which one the customers
actually care about or drive the best results,
and then rank them from the most important to least important. Okay? Now,
a product can have a ton of different benefits, okay?
But the ones that the people actually care about are the ones that we should be
leading with as, as a marketer, as a, as an editor.
And sometimes it's,
it takes a little bit of digging and refinement and a lot of data to understand
what that one really is, because when people, uh, they develop new products,
they don't quite understand a hundred percent. If it's a brand new product,
they don't know which one,
which benefit customers really care about unless they're, uh, they're,
you know, learning from their competitors or whatever.
But they can extract what they know from another competitor,
but they can have a completely different brand.
And then the benefits change because the brand is different.
So one thing to understand about a benefit is the opposite of it
is a pain point. Okay? So, for example, the benefit of,
you know, having this phone is I can call anybody at any time.
I can search the web, I can do, I can function so much more.
It's like having a computer in my hand right now. The opposite of that is,
okay, what if I take that all away from you?
What if you don't have a phone that has five G technology and can
call anyone at any time and do all these programs?
Then it becomes a pain point for me, right?
So when you take away a benefit becomes a pain,
which is typically linked to a negative emotion, all right?
We don't like experiencing pain. When we, when we experience pain,
then we feel like there's some sort of, we're we're missing.
We want it to be resolved immediately.
And here are different emotions of negative pain or negative emotions, uh,
that I would say marketers and, and, and us use,
uh, to twist the knife to,
to get deeper in the emotional,
I would say investment in something you have fear, anxiety, insecurity,
physical pain, frustration, anger. If you,
if you lead with some of these pain points, uh,
you will be able to trigger some people, uh, and, and, and get them to convert.
Because, you know, if you ever, it's like stranded in,
in the desert and you needed this, like, there you go. You've got,
you've got yourself a frustration pain point, or, uh,
are you afraid of people breaking into your house?
That becomes a fear pain point. You know, are you afraid of,
of injuring yourself? Uh, on the, on the football field, boom,
that's a physical pain point. You know, are you stressed outta your mind?
You can't get any work done. That's an anxiety pain point. You know, are you,
are you super angered at the government for taking your money? Right?
Are you embarrassed of your, of your skin? That's insecurity.
So all these different pain points are different hooks potentially,
and different people will resonate with different, different emotions.
So you have to test which one actually is the key one, because like I said,
the opposite of a pain point is a benefit. So when you introduce a pain point,
the, the benefit should immediately follow.
Whenever a person feels this pain or negative emotion,
they want an an immediate solution. It's like getting a cut,
and you need a bandaid. You need, you need something, you need a quick fix.
So it's one of those things where if you can present that problem,
that pain point right off the bat, and your product is a solution, then boom,
you know, you've,
you provided them an opportunity to get interested in your product,
and that's where your product comes in. Okay? So this brand is called Ola.
We actually did some creative for them not too long ago.
And I'm gonna use this as a primary example for breaking this down.
All right? Remember, I,
I added this in because it's really important to remember,
especially if you're a freelancer, if you're an agency,
if you worked with a lot of different clients,
sometimes websites or product owners don't even know or accurately describe
their own products, key benefits, okay? This has happened so many times for us.
We've worked with, I'm telling you,
we've worked with hundreds of different brands, and sometimes they have no clue.
They just hire us, and they're like, okay, yeah, make it sell.
But they haven't done any of the research in terms of the data.
They haven't tested anything, and they're just,
they're just stoked on their product,
but they don't know exactly what it is about their product that makes it sell.
And they hire us to do all that work for them, okay? So if you don't,
if you come across a situation where you don't have that information, or you,
you feel like, Hey, this doesn't feel right, do your own research, okay?
Like I said, you gotta be doing your own research.
So here's how you can verify accurate product benefits. Uh,
I use this little hack, this little tool, this little shortcut pretty often.
Actually, step one,
use Amazon and search a similar product, okay? Go to amazon.com.
Type in for, in this case, the product that we're using as example,
it's a belly oil stretch mark, uh, serum cream,
whatever you wanna call it. And, uh, type that in. Okay?
So you're gonna get a ton of, ton of options. Just go with the top one. Next,
you're gonna find the highest rated product by the reviews, okay?
And that was actually this one right here.
So you've got the Palmer's cocoa butter formula, I think has 20,000 views,
a 20,000 reviews. So I'm like, alright, let's go there next,
find the highest rated product by reviews. Okay? That's clearly the one.
Let's click on it next, scroll down and read the five star reviews. Okay?
These are gonna be sorted by recency. So here we go.
We've got a ton of reviews already showing up. Here's the thing with Amazon,
you don't know if it's bought, you don't know if they're authentic,
but it's the,
it's a good place as an aggregate for reviews for any type of product, uh,
versus going to websites. 'cause you know, like sometimes even web, I mean,
lots of times websites are fake too,
so it's hard to find like real authentic stuff these days. Um,
that's why like Reddit or, or, you know,
typ like some social pages that aren't, if,
if you're not being compensated for it, they're gonna give you the truth.
So step four,
I would say read 10 reviews or so, get a good feel for the product's,
benefits and the customer's recurring pain points. All right?
Once you start reading a lot of these, these reviews, you're gonna understand,
okay, like, oh, this, this type of person, um, you know,
you really want to immerse yourself into that world.
'cause when you jump into an edit or you jump into something cold,
it's like you haven't warmed up to it. You're, you're,
you're gonna be super lost. Um,
it's like going into like a crowd of people and like just being, hey, like,
here I am. Like, if you start talking to people on an individual level first,
introducing yourself, getting to know them. Once you meet everybody in the room,
then you feel more comfortable with who you're talking to. Like,
if you're about to present something, um, then you can kind of,
you can adjust how you're gonna present because you know who you're actually
speaking to. If you're just like, okay, this is just an audience, but they're,
you know, it, it's part of the research phase, obviously.
So the next step is identifying common keywords, pain points,
and use cases. All right? So a lot of, like, if,
if you don't have the trained eye for this, uh, just 'cause I've,
we've done it so many times, you wanna be looking for certain keywords, okay?
So I've underlined them for you. I'm obsessed with every product in this bundle,
blah, blah, blah. I'm 17 weeks pregnant. Okay, pregnant,
that's a key word. Still no stretch marks another key word. Um,
I love the smell and how moisturizing it is. I normally hate lotion, da da da.
But these products dry pretty quickly. No sticky residue filling.
We'll definitely continue using postpartum as well. Alright?
So a lot of different keywords in here,
and I know that there's probably tools out there right now that will do this for
you. But you know, if you don't wanna pay extra money to get those made or to,
to subscribe to those, you can just do it manually. That's what I do.
You can get a good, a good enough feel for it. So, stretch marks pregnant,
moisturizing, no sticky residue postpartum. This is all telling me like, okay,
now I'm entering this world that I, I have a more clearer understanding of.
Here we are, pregnant stretch marks loves the smell, moisturizing dries quickly.
So this is telling me, all right,
I'm just like letting my subconscious absorb all this information, right?
Example number two, pregnancy, itchiness. Oh,
I didn't even know that was a thing, even though I have kids, like,
I didn't even know pregnant women get itchy. Stopping the, it like,
what did you say? I was told by a friend about the oil, tummy butter,
and even the oil to stop itchiness immediately bought online after using for one
full day, the itchiness disappeared. Okay? Itchiness disappeared. Wow,
that's a big, it's a big claim, but it's also very powerful.
No stretch marks or itchiness in sight. Dang right there.
That itself could be used as a headline.
Best money spent on spent this pregnancy by far.
All of these golden and golden nuggets for copy. Golden nuggets for angles,
golden nuggets for hooks. I'm telling you, they've done all the work for you.
Steal first, innovate later, it's gonna save you a s**t ton of time. Alright,
so I've broken it down over here in terms of
the example of benefits. You have the product, all right?
We've got the nourishing belly oil,
and we've got our benefits listed from one to five. And, uh,
I'm gonna go through the other different sections here. The pain point,
negative emotions and positive emotions,
because everything is linked to a,
a benefit is linked to an emotion. And you have to understand that, uh,
they're not just these made up things, these made up words that,
that brands will, will mention about their product, but it's actually linked to,
to an emotional reaction.
So benefit number one reduces stretch marks during pregnancy and postpartum
number two reduces scars. Number three, smooths and confirms and brighten skin.
Number four helps uneven skin tone, aging. Number five, dry and sensitive skin.
All right, so this was just my hypothesis of like, you know,
doing my own research, but this can change,
this can totally change in terms of priority. So, you know, if,
if we lead as a, as a create ad creative benefit, number one,
which is reducing stretch marks, right?
We're gonna appeal to people who are looking for a stretch mark solution.
But let's say we lead with, uh,
reducing scars and we start with scars as the hook,
it's gonna attract a completely different person. Person.
And all of these benefits could potentially be winning angles on their own.
So leading with one, uh, you know, the leading with one,
the primary benefit is definitely a good start,
but tests the other benefits and see if they attract, um,
a different type of consumer, different audience. And that's how you,
that's how you scale. Alright,
moving to the next column to pain points. Alright,
so remember what I said about the opposite of a benefit. It's a pain point.
So excuse me, if you have stretch marks, you know,
having stretch marks itself, excuse me, is the pain point, right?
If you have scars, you get scars from pregnancy. These, right?
So it's like I have the scar, I don't want the scar, I have the stretch mark.
I don't want the stretch mark. I have loose dual skin.
I want smooth and brighter skin. I have uneven skin tone.
I want nice and balanced skin tone. I have itchy skin. I want,
you know, I want, um, I want smooth skin. I want un itchy skin. I want relief.
Okay? So very clearly, I think this is a very binary,
easy example to follow, but it's, it's very important to know, um,
because when you're, when you're doing any ads, like leading with pain points,
you wanna showcase the solution right afterwards. Okay? So you've got the,
you've got the stretch marks show, no stretch marks. You've got loose skin,
show tight skin, you've got uneven skin tone, show flawless skin,
you've got itchy eczema, you've got perfect skin, right?
So this is that before and after that problem, solution, um,
format. And it's very important as an editor, as a marketer to, to,
to have that dialed in. Alright? Next is,
what are these pain points linked to emotionally that are considered negative
emotions? Okay? So when you have stretch marks,
the typical emotions are probably insecurity. Uh, insecurity.
You don't wanna show it off to anybody. You have fear of of, of showing it off.
Potentially you have anxiety because they won't go away.
Frustration because maybe you've used everything and it doesn't work, right?
You're frustrated with that or you're frustrated that after having kids, you,
you, you don't look the same again. Uh, reducing scars,
very similar I would say to stretch marks. Um, like I said,
insecurity, fear, anxiety, frustration.
These are all very common pain points or negative emotions that, um,
that the customer will feel. They actually feel those things.
And I'm sure you've experienced it before where you're like, ah,
I wish I fricking had this. Like, for me, I have eczema, so I get, I, you know,
I've, I have frustration around eczema. I have insecurity around eczema.
'cause it'll show up and it's, it's not pretty, uh, it's not comfortable.
It creates physical pain for me. Uh, especially if like, it,
it flares up, right? So I'm always looking for a solution to, to,
to resolve that, even though it's something that can never go away.
So a person feels insecure because she can't show off her body in the same way
or to her partner or in public, all right? That's, you know,
when you start to dig into the why, okay? Why does this person feel insecure?
It's because because of this reason. She, she doesn't feel the same,
she doesn't feel confident in her body, okay?
Person feels fear because people might judge her appearance.
I'm sure you felt that before, right? This is,
this is starting to put yourself in the customer's shoes.
Person feels anxiety because she doesn't want to wanna get surgery to fix the
problem. It's very important to understand that like anxiety, and it's like,
I don't want to go under the knife. I don't want to spend X amount of money,
I don't have that kind of money. That's, that creates anxiety.
People feels frus people,
person feels frustration because he's tried so many things and none of them
work. You've probably been through that yourself in some way, shape, or form.
Alright? So after you've gone through the negative emotions you wanna install,
what are the positive emotions that this person could potentially feel by
overcoming all these negative emotions, you know, essentially with that product,
right? So if, if they don't have any more insecurity, fear, anxiety,
frustration over their stretch marks, they're gonna feel confident,
worry free and happy. And I listen that all the way through down,
because you know, very similarly,
all of these are are physical transformations of their own body that
will give them the confidence and the worry-free life and the happiness
that they're looking for, as well as the comfortability,
because they won't be itching themselves so much. That product solves it.
So essentially you're not selling a stretch mark cream people,
okay? You are selling confidence. You're selling confidence in a bottle.
So when you're showing this in, in an advert, okay,
you're starting with the pain, you're providing the solution,
but you're also in the UGCs in the rest of the video,
you're showing women who are so confident in themselves, who are so happy,
who are so stoked, who are showing off their bodies. See, that is the outcome.
You're selling the outcome, all right? You're not selling the process.
You're not selling, oh, apply this thing and circulate it around your,
your stretch marks. People don't care.
They want the after they want the outcome. Okay?
Very important. So to narrow down your benefits,
ask what are the top three problems this problem solves? All right?
I think we can get very detailed with all the different benefits of something,
but at the end of the day, your customer only cares about a few of them,
and that's the one you should be focusing on.
So these three top three benefits should be your primary focus in the creative,
and then let the landing page do the rest of the selling. Alright?
I, I, I come across this a lot,
especially in the agency world where the brand owner wants to put every single
potential benefit and feature into the advert.
And that's just not okay because no one cares, okay? It's just too much.
That's not our objective. That's what the website's for,
that's what the land's for. Let that do the rest of the selling.
Let us let the advert let the video get, grab attention,
get them excited about it, and get them to click. That's our main objective,
okay? When you go to the landing page,
you'll see all the additional benefits that the customer will read.
Let the c r o team handle that, okay?
That's a whole entire different process of optimization.
But know that our job is to get the click.
Next stage is the primary features, okay? So remember features tell,
tell us what the product is. Benefits sell, features tell.
So these are the features for the nourishing belly oil or here are some
categories for features, okay? Product specifications, the weight, the size,
the components, et cetera. Shipping box, how it works,
ingredients, certifications, quality ratings, right? It,
it's just all the physical stuff, the physicality of it. Okay?
Those are the features. What does it come with? That's a feature.
Now how does it, how does it affect your life?
How does it benefit you because of that feature. That's a completely different,
uh, story.
So features can definitely be things that you lead with if it's
important enough for the customer.
So here's some examples of features. Okay?
So their number one feature is that it's developed with Harvard dermatologists
and OBGYNs. It's got a blend of 15 organic natural plant oils.
Um, it's a fast absorbing oil. It smells really good.
E w g certified, hypoallergenic, all those things. And, you know,
it's relatively small bottle, but the different types of feature types,
certifications, ingredients, you know, these are all things that are,
that come along with the product, the physicality of the product. You get it,
but while buying it, there's no, there's no question about it. Okay?
Features tell and benefits sell depending on the product type positioning,
the features over the benefits can vary. Like I said, it really depends.
If it's a feature based product, then we're gonna lead with features.
But if it's a benefit driven product, we're gonna lead with the benefits. Okay?
Take the iPhone 14, for example. This,
I went to the Apple website and their U S P unique selling props is,
is purely feature-based, magical new way to interact with iPhone.
Groundbreaking safety features.
They even say the word features designed to save lives, okay?
Innovative 48 megapixel camera right there.
It's telling you it's a feature because it's a physical component of the product
for mind-blowing detail. There's the, um, the benefit, right?
With the 48 megapixel camera, you have mind-blowing detail.
So it's a feature then benefit, all powered by the ultimate smartphone chip.
There you go. There's another feature, ultimate smartphone ship.
Those are physical designed for durability.
Okay? Durability. It could go both ways. That is definitely a benefit,
but then it goes into ceramic shield, okay? That is a feature,
it's a physical c ceramic part tougher than any smartphone.
Okay? That's, that's definitely a benefit. Um, water resistant, that's a,
that's a feature. Surgical grade, stainless steel, definitely a feature.
6.1, 6.7 display sizes. When you start getting into the, the, the micro,
the very granular details, boom, you're talking about features. All right?
So depending on what primary feature or benefit to focus on,
will determine on the overall marketing strategy.
So whoever's coming up with this,
whoever's doing the research is gonna determine, all right,
we're gonna be leading with these features because we feel in the marketplace,
that's what people want to see. All right?
You can always follow up with the benefit, uh, to support the feature,
I think is a really big thing. Uh, really drives it home. Um,
so if we're talking about the waterproof feature, you know, um,
you can say, okay, it's made of the ceramic, da, da, da, but the,
the benefit would be, okay, someone tells, okay,
I've dropped my phone into the toilet so many times and it saved me
so much money, okay?
It saved me so much money from having to replace my phone because it's
waterproof. Boom. That is a benefit.
That's helping support the person's life. Now you can transform all of those,
this screen, all right, I have bad eyes, so now I can see more clearly. Boom,
that's a benefit. There's no absolute right answer.
It's all about testing different angles, messages,
and benefits to see which one actually resonates with the ideal customer.
Like I said, there's no magic bullet for, for,
for creative and for for marketing.
You can definitely assess what's working and start from there,
but at the end of the day, your data is gonna be sacred to you.
So you need to be testing and, and learning from that.
The last stage to product research is gonna be your use cases, all right?
Use cases are the various ways to use this product. Um,
I think this is super important. I learned this from another agency, uh,
working with them for a long time is in a strategy call we'd always talk about,
okay, what are the different ways to use this product? Alright?
So different use cases you can use the product for stretch marks,
obviously scars, dry patches, itchy areas, belly,
arms, leg face, any type of body part.
You can even go further with this with different use cases, okay? Like, um,
where would you use it, you know, or use it in the bathroom.
Would you use it in in the car?
Would you use it in your bedroom? Right? There's so many, uh, uh,
physical use cases that you can, you can do as well or location-based use cases.
And then you can do,
you can go even further with like avatar use cases or like different types of
avatars who would use it, right?
So here's an example of like actual use cases, all right? So if you have,
if you have that pregnancy scar or pregnancy stretch marks right there,
that's gonna help that. If you have dry skin on your face,
if you have itchy arms or eczema, this is gonna help with that. But,
um, these are like additional,
additional benefits that the customer might seem like, oh, wow,
I didn't even know it was, it was used for all those things. And I,
I actually didn't know that either until it was, it was shown to me.
So a customer won't, won't do anything unless they're told, okay?
Unless it says specifically on your site or your product that it,
it helps with certain thing, then they'll do it. But you've got,
you've gotta lead to horse, the water.